<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <title>Aayushya&#x27;s Blog</title>
    <link href="https://aayushyaranjan.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://aayushyaranjan.github.io" />
    <updated>2023-03-16T18:28:01+05:30</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Aayushya Ranjan</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://aayushyaranjan.github.io</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Testing testing... Earth to Hari Nagar</title>
        <author>
            <name>Aayushya Ranjan</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://aayushyaranjan.github.io/testing-testing-earth-to-hari-nagar.html"/>
        <id>https://aayushyaranjan.github.io/testing-testing-earth-to-hari-nagar.html</id>

        <updated>2023-03-16T18:28:01+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Hari Nagar, I have been living here since the last 8 years and I still don't know shit about the place. It's spooky at night, playful in the evening and eerily quiet in the afternoons. The best time to visit this corner of West Delhi&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>Hari Nagar, I have been living here since the last 8 years and I still don't know shit about the place. It's spooky at night, playful in the evening and eerily quiet in the afternoons. The best time to visit this corner of West Delhi is 5 in the morning. You can hear a small commotion but try smoking in the clean morning air. There is nothing like it.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Draft Post</title>
        <author>
            <name>Aayushya Ranjan</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://aayushyaranjan.github.io/draft-post.html"/>
        <id>https://aayushyaranjan.github.io/draft-post.html</id>

        <updated>2023-03-16T17:35:50+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    I am usually bogged down by the tech savvy-ness of the simple task of showing your work to the world. I wouldn't probably be able to survive if I was stranded in a jungle. I would want to be eaten by a tiger. It has&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>I am usually bogged down by the tech savvy-ness of the simple task of showing your work to the world. I wouldn't probably be able to survive if I was stranded in a jungle. I would want to be eaten by a tiger. It has nice colours. I am not racist, although I am not fond of Bengali people.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
