<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <title>aayushya.in</title>
    <link href="https://aayushya.in/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://aayushya.in" />
    <updated>2023-03-17T00:54:46+05:30</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Aayushya Ranjan</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://aayushya.in</id>

    <entry>
        <title>The Dark Yellow Filament Bulb</title>
        <author>
            <name>Aayushya Ranjan</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://aayushya.in/the-dark-yellow-filament-bulb.html"/>
        <id>https://aayushya.in/the-dark-yellow-filament-bulb.html</id>

        <updated>2023-03-17T00:54:46+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                     Let me tell you about yellow. Not the kind of&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p> Let me tell you about yellow. Not the kind of yellow you see in Spring, not marigolds, not the bright coloured sari Mummy used to wear on _Vasant Panchami_. I am talking about the colour of the old single light bulb in my room in Govindpuri. The area is the dingy underbelly of South Delhi, it is filled by immigrants, students, and the people the world doesn’t care about. Even in bright summers, the light doesn’t reach inside the lanes. The lanes are perpetually dark and always very loud. I go down everyday to a small _chai _stall to have a cup in peace but noise constantly pervades the air. There is no respite from the filth in air, in sound, and more so in my own mind. I came here to be a photographer but I think  my camera hates me. Anyway, I was talking about the colour yellow. I can’t seem to escape from it. I stay in a small makeshift room on the terrace of someone’s house. I think they had it constructed to be used as a store room but my incessant begging convinced them to let me stay. They gave me an old mattress and a dusty table fan they don’t use. I never complain. I haven’t been upto much, something which Papa always finds the need to mention whenever I call him to ask for money. The room is lit up by the singular bulb which must’ve been installed by the owners and never been touched since. The tungsten in the bulb hasn’t given out but the surrounding glass is almost black. This contrast between the filament and the glass gives out a dark yellow colour. In this colour every crevice and mould of the room and of my body is accentuated. The room is stale. It reeks of my sweat and concrete. I don’t have any people to invite here but even if I did I probably wouldn’t want them to come here. I don’t mind the destitute condition, I feel that I deserve to live in a place no better than this because day in and day out all I can muster up to do is keep laying down, stare at the ceiling and blame everything that went wrong in my life. Mummy still talks of hope. She keeps reassuring me that all I need to do is pick up a camera, find a project and eventually move towards the dream of publishing my own photo-book. But her voice, her optimism, her belief in me has started to hurt my ears. I can’t seem to stand her voice. So whenever she talks to me, I stare at the dark yellow illuminated wall of the room, fixate on a point, and try to drone out her voice. Often in our conversations, she starts to cry but tries to hide it. Her voice cracks and becomes higher but she tries her best to keep me from knowing that she isn’t crying. Crying would mean that she too is losing hope and she can’t have that for me. The city is also very unforgiving in the summer. The afternoons in the room are unbearable. I only wear a white sleeveless vest and some shorts and yet I feel the heat eating away at me.   <br> I know I keep going on about my life, but even if I tried my best I would only sound stupid if I tried to talk about anything else. My life and how I survive every minute of it is the only thing I think I can talk about coherently. Anything else is simply just half-baked knowledge which I try to pretend I to know about. But I don’t want to mislead you into thinking I am wise, well read or someone with a lot of opinions. I am none of that. I told you that my camera hates me, allow me to tell you a little more about that. I picked up the camera in school and fell in love with it. It’s a small mirror-less and I always found the opportunity to take it out and photograph everything. I remember once when Papa had a few people over and they were drinking and laughing through the evening. I saw Mummy and Papa sitting together and laughing very loudly. I instinctively picked up the camera and took a photograph of them. Papa’s hands were resting on his leg, in one hand he had his whiskey and in the other he had a fistful of salted peanuts. Mummy doesn’t drink so she wasn’t holding anything but she had one of her hands on Papa’s shoulder. I keep looking at the photograph. It has held in place a moment where they are happy. This is probably why I decided to be a photographer. I found it to be a sort of superpower I had where I can capture time and nothing in the world then could taint that moment that was captured. But my camera hates me. Whenever I take it out now, I am lost when I look from the viewfinder. I don’t see any happiness I would want to capture. I only see my empty room and the dark yellow tungsten bulb. This camera once was an extension of my arm, it never failed me. I have hoards of photographs from the times which I truly felt content and happy once upon a time. Only thing I can find when I look out of it now is the stale room that is intent on swallowing me whole. <br>                                                                        ထ<br><br> Let me now tell you about red. The kind of red which is the colour of Palaash and Semal flowers, the kind of red which is the colour of my blood. The city now has broken into spring. There is a small hint of the past winter in the air and the air is always a comfortable breeze. I decided to take a walk today in late afternoon. The sunlight was less harsh and I wanted to have some _chai_. As I was going out I saw my camera in the corner of the room and decided it to carry it with me, I had no intention to photograph anything but because of some mysterious instinct I still picked it up. I got down to see my usual spot closed. Despite my usual judgement, I decided to walk a little farther from Govindpuri to a quieter area nearby, CR Park. Now CR Park was established in an effort to accommodate the Bengali refugee population coming to Delhi after the partition and the ‘71 Bangladesh war. It has many markets but my favourite is the one with a middle-aged jolly Bengali man who plays music from an old radio while making _chai. _The market also has a thriving fish market but despite the stereotype it’s quite peaceful. I go there today and just as I sit down with a small plastic tea cup, I look up and get completely stupefied. It must have been 6 in the evening and the sky was the shade of deep red. Something I never had seen before. There were faint clouds which were reflecting the setting sun. The sky was lit up so brilliantly that I couldn’t take my eyes off of it. It was then after months of agony, my hand moved on it’s own. I looked in the viewfinder and photographed the moment. It wasn’t only a mere photograph of the sky, it was the moment I could feel my eyes well up, my throat close and was overcome with hope. My camera wasn’t angry at me anymore, I wasn’t angry at myself anymore. I kept the camera on the side, wiped my tears before anyone else could notice them and finished my tea. I ended up sitting there for quite some time. I was just taking in the first time in months I have been able to breathe and look forward to the next moment not simply keep trying to survive from minute to minute. I started to walk back when I started to hear the shops being closed for the day. I rushed over to a store,</p>
<blockquote>
<p><br>- Bhaiya?  <br>- Ji? (Yes?)  <br>- Ek Safed Light Bulb dijie na. (Can you please give me a white light bulb.)                                  <br><br></p>
</blockquote>
<p>                                                                      ထ</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>The Time I did not Drown</title>
        <author>
            <name>Aayushya Ranjan</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://aayushya.in/the-time-i-did-not-drown.html"/>
        <id>https://aayushya.in/the-time-i-did-not-drown.html</id>

        <updated>2023-03-17T00:51:11+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    I once jumped into a river. I had an unrealistic&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p class="md-end-block md-p"><span class="md-plain">I once jumped into a river. I had an unrealistic confidence that as soon as I will find myself in the water, I will swim. I jumped to find my head completely submerged. I remember that I was able to see the river beneath with absolute clarity. Yet, at that moment, I could not breathe at all. I came to realize that I can very well drown, my senses completely froze. My hands and legs felt the current and the heaviness of the water. Instinctively, I started to flop my hands to cause a ruckus for someone to notice. </span></p>
<p class="md-end-block md-p"><span class="md-plain">Since I was wearing a life jacket, my body started to float. I was too frantic to realize that I wasn't in any actual danger. The river had a strong current that day thus I felt myself floating further away from my raft. I moved my head to see my petrified parents looking over from the raft. Mummy was trying to throw a paddle toward me to latch onto but the current kept taking me away.</span></p>
<p class="md-end-block md-p"><span class="md-plain">A feverish panic set in and I was completely paralyzed. At that moment I wanted nothing more than to get out of the water. Every ounce of myself was silently screaming for help but my body wasn't complying. It had become complacent, almost as if it had a mind. Soon after someone came swimming towards me and handed me one hand of a paddle which I immediately grasped. </span></p>
<p class="md-end-block md-p"><span class="md-plain">I will be honest with you. I don't remember much of the trip afterward. Just a few fragmented moments here and there. However, the only thing I can remember vividly is the inertia. Sometimes while showering, I get a little out of breath as the water clogs up my nose. Soon as this happens, the memory of the river comes right back. My body had resigned. Even when my mind was constantly panicking to find solutions, my body accepted and resigned itself to complacent inertia. </span></p>
<p class="md-end-block md-p"><span class="md-plain">Every time I pick up the pen to write. I fight the very same inertia. My fingers pain, my mind rejects the sentences, I constantly panic about the quality of the writing and my mind often goes to the possibility of public humiliation. </span></p>
<p class="md-end-block md-p"><span class="md-plain">Not writing for me is the same as drowning. I will drown in a life of mediocracy and regret. I will drown and never pick up the pen again. I don't want to look back and see this as an effort to build a childish utopia.</span></p>
<p class="md-end-block md-p md-focus"><span class="md-plain md-expand">This time there is no one swimming toward me. This time somehow I will have to wash ashore. All words here are my attempts to flop around inside the river. I can't see the bottom of the river nor can I see the light from above. Just clear water and my attempts to break the inertia, one word at a time.</span></p>
<figure class="post__image align-center"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://aayushya.in/media/posts/4/Photo-for-newsletter-Drowing-2.jpg" alt="" width="578" height="578" sizes="(min-width: 1500px) calc(7.87vw + 610px), (min-width: 900px) calc(44.48vw + 68px), (min-width: 780px) calc(8vw + 604px), calc(84.35vw + 23px)" srcset="https://aayushya.in/media/posts/4/responsive/Photo-for-newsletter-Drowing-2-xs.jpg 300w ,https://aayushya.in/media/posts/4/responsive/Photo-for-newsletter-Drowing-2-sm.jpg 480w ,https://aayushya.in/media/posts/4/responsive/Photo-for-newsletter-Drowing-2-md.jpg 768w"></figure>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>How Dare the Sun?</title>
        <author>
            <name>Aayushya Ranjan</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://aayushya.in/how-dare-the-sun.html"/>
        <id>https://aayushya.in/how-dare-the-sun.html</id>

        <updated>2023-03-17T00:44:10+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Today I read that the sun is going to swallow&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p class="md-end-block md-p"><span class="md-plain">Today I read that the sun is going to swallow the earth in 5 Billion years. The earth and life as we know it is going to be utterly destroyed just as mysteriously it was created.</span></p>
<p class="md-end-block md-p"><span class="md-plain">I don't have a recollection of the earth being born. I don't know what life was in the last century let alone from the beginning of material time. The prospect of dying from a world-ending catastrophe has been the foremost fear I have always had. Existentialists, therapy sessions helped me get through the fear with various insights. All these insights had but one thing in common, "This moment will not come back, savour it."</span></p>
<p class="md-end-block md-p"><span class="md-plain">But what exactly is savouring it? Savouring a dish or a drink would constitute that I should eat or drink slowly. Take my time to take in the delicate taste.</span></p>
<p class="md-end-block md-p"><span class="md-plain">I truly believe that life can't be savoured. I am almost 26 and I have only been able to savour a handful of small moments. Moments which are embedded in my skin.</span></p>
<ul class="ul-list" data-mark="-">
<li class="md-list-item">
<p class="md-end-block md-p"><span class="md-plain">A throat itch after a concert or a long day with friends.</span></p>
</li>
<li class="md-list-item">
<p class="md-end-block md-p"><span class="md-plain">Warm sun on a cold Delhi morning.</span></p>
</li>
<li class="md-list-item">
<p class="md-end-block md-p"><span class="md-plain">The smell of papad.</span></p>
</li>
<li class="md-list-item">
<p class="md-end-block md-p"><span class="md-plain">The scent of a bookstore.</span></p>
</li>
<li class="md-list-item">
<p class="md-end-block md-p"><span class="md-plain">Mummy &amp; Papa's embrace.</span></p>
</li>
<li class="md-list-item">
<p class="md-end-block md-p"><span class="md-plain">The burn of flaming ash from a cigarette dropped right onto my exposed skin.</span></p>
</li>
<li class="md-list-item">
<p class="md-end-block md-p"><span class="md-plain">Biting into a juicy kebab after a long day.</span></p>
</li>
<li class="md-list-item">
<p class="md-end-block md-p"><span class="md-plain">Looking at someone's photograph long after they have left your life.</span></p>
</li>
</ul>
<p class="md-end-block md-p"><span class="md-plain">These among many other things are what I carry around on my shoulders. I should very well carry a placard announcing, "I have lived too!"</span></p>
<p class="md-end-block md-p"><span class="md-plain">And indeed I have, I have lived in every new dish I tried. I have lived in every cigarette I shared with my sister. I have lived in every song I sang with my friends. I have lived every time I forgave myself for being terrible at something.</span></p>
<p class="md-end-block md-p"><span class="md-plain">So if the sun takes the earth, I hope it collapses on its own weight and gets destroyed to bits. How dare he take the lives which we lived or unlived?</span></p>
<p class="md-end-block md-p md-focus"><span class="md-plain md-expand">How dare the sun?</span></p>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://aayushya.in/media/posts/3/autodraw-11_11_2022.png" alt="" width="3072" height="1655" sizes="(min-width: 1500px) calc(7.87vw + 610px), (min-width: 900px) calc(44.48vw + 68px), (min-width: 780px) calc(8vw + 604px), calc(84.35vw + 23px)" srcset="https://aayushya.in/media/posts/3/responsive/autodraw-11_11_2022-xs.png 300w ,https://aayushya.in/media/posts/3/responsive/autodraw-11_11_2022-sm.png 480w ,https://aayushya.in/media/posts/3/responsive/autodraw-11_11_2022-md.png 768w"></figure>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
